Esteban Sánchez

emsg94@gmail.com • +34 674 23 67 09 linkedin.com/in/estebanmsg • github.com/esan94 • medium.com/@emsg94

About me

I am what I call a *Full Stack Data Scientist*. In these 6 years of experience, I took the chance of participating in all phases of a data project. Definition, expectations and development of the solutions, search for the best models that meet the business needs, putting the solutions into production and monitoring them to define the next iterations. Also, I love to communicate, that is why I like to participate in events or transfer my knowledge to coworkers.

Academic Experience

UNIVERSIDAD POLITÉCNICA DE MADRID (UPM)

Collaborative Researcher in Complex Systems (GSC)

Remote, 2023.04 – Currently

R&D in social behaviour in social networks as Twitter through socio-physics models.

Professional Experience

BRAVENT

Senior Data Scientist - AI, full time job

Remote, 2023.06 - Currently

- R&D in NLP and computer vision solutions.
- Design AI solutions and managing tasks to success on projects.

CQISENSE

Senior Data Scientist, full time job

Remote, 2023.04 - 2023.05

• Analyse features with impact in churn and develop and optimize scorecard models.

DECIDE4AI

Senior Data Scientist, full time job

Remote, 2021.08 - 2023.04

- Develop and deploy solutions machine learning based according to business. These solutions involve recommender systems, binary classification models, forecasting methods, segmentation models and buy propensity score following MLOps standard.
- Manage a small team of 3 supervising the quality of projects and providing support to the colleagues.
- Develop and defend PoC and proposals to new clients.

VODAFONE GROUP

Specialist Data Scientist, full time job

Hybrid, 2019.08 – 2021.03

- Develop and deploy ETL and data based products to improve the pricing for business.
- Develop clustering models to gain insights about the behavior of the clients.

ERNST & YOUNG

Data Scientist, full time job

Madrid, 2019.04 - 2019.06

INDIZEN TECHNOLOGY & BUSINESS CONFLUENCE

Data Scientist Junior, full time job

Madrid, 2017.10 - 2019.04

Educator Experience

THE BRIDGE - DIGITAL TALENT ACCELERATOR

Data Scientist Lead Instructor, part time job

Madrid, 2020.02 - 2021.10

IMMUNE TECHNOLOGY INSTITUTE

Unsupervised learning instructor, part time job

Remote, 2020.06

Education

UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DE EDUCACIÓN A DISTANCIA (UNED)

Master in Physics of Complex Systems

Madrid, 2020.09 - 2023.10

Honors in Fluctuations in Dynamical Systems and Statistical Mechanics of Complex Fluids.

KSHOOL

Master in Data Science

Madrid, 2018.10 - 2019.05

UNIVERSIDAD COMPLUTENSE DE MADRID (UCM)

Degree in Physics, Fundamental Physics Specialization

Madrid, 2012.09 - 2018.02

Related Education

COURSERA

Machine Learning Andrew NG Deep Learning Specialization

CODE ACADEMY

Full Stack Engineer

Currently

Publications & Participations

T3CH FEST

Course "Who knows you better, the AI or your friend? Setting up a recommendation engine." t3chfest.es/2023/programa/quien-te-conoce-mejor-ia-motor-recomendacion

Madrid, 2023.02.25

PvConEs

Manage the talks proposed by the company.

charlas.2022.es.pycon.org/pycones2022/talk/NXGNSB/

Granada, 2022.10.02

PHYSICS NUCLEAR B

Shannon entropy and particle decays.

doi.org/10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2018.04.003

2018.04.10

Personal Work Experience

ALGORITHMIC TRADER

2021.09 - Currently

- Develop trading strategies based on technical indicators.
- Automatize chartist trading strategies.
- Research and develop trading strategies based on artificial intelligence and how to use AI to improve strategies.
- Optimize assets management.

Technical Skills	Domain Skills	Soft Skills
Python, PySpark, GIT, SQL Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Keras	Recommender Systems Classification Models	Communicator Sense of humor
Tensorflow, Flask, Darts, XGBoost	Clustering Models	Autodidact
Shap, Pytorch, Transformers	Forecasting, NLP, CV	Resilient
AWS, SageMaker, GCP, Airflow, Azure NetworkX, SSD, EfficientNet	Churn	Entrepreneurial mindset